# Joseph Mania

Nairobi, Kenya | +254 740 743 521 | martialmania19@gmail.com

Website: https://techmaniac649449135.wordpress.com

Github: https://github.com/maniamartial

#### CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am an enthusiastic, reliable, self-motivated and proactive software developer with an eye for detail. I aim to exceed expectations over and above my normal duties and responsibilities. I am results-driven, hardworking, and a proven resource to ensure that a company enjoys a competitive edge at all levels. My goals in my developer career are to create and optimize the best web software for clients and maximize my training experience, program development skills, and abilities. Lastly, I desire to learn and work with experienced developers to gain more knowledge on solving problems using tech. I look forward to joining your team.

#### **EDUCATION**

Kenyatta University 2019 - Present

Computer Science

Nyang'ori School 2015 - 2018

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education Grade A-

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Fruitful Labs | Nairobi, Kenya

Nov 2021 - Dec 2022

Backend Developer

- Created high-performance and scalable RESTful APIs for data-intensive applications.
- Built a microservice-based architecture to increase system efficiency and stability.
- Developed automated testing and deployment pipelines to reduce manual intervention and improve release quality.
- Debugged complex issues in the production environment and implemented permanent solutions to prevent recurrence.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver end-to-end software solutions.

#### Iconcept Media | California, USA

Nov 2021 - Dec 2022

Technical Writer

- Creating technical documentation such as user manuals, installation guides, and online help documentation.
- Collaborate with development teams to understand the technical details of products

• Translate that information into clear, concise, and accurate documentation for users.

# Lux Academy | Nairobi, Kenya

Feb 2021 - Aug 2021

Backend Developer Intern

- Designed, built, and implemented RESTful APIs that were secure, reliable, and easy to consume.
- Worked on optimizing the performance and scalability of existing applications to accommodate increasing user traffic.
- Working on SEO to create fast loading of pages

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Water Ecommerce**

- Developed a fully functional e-commerce website using the Django framework.
- Integrated payment methods and delivery functionality into the website.
- Ensured the website was user-friendly and easy to navigate.
- Code for the project. (https://github.com/maniamartial/Ecommerce Django)

# Task Manager

- Created a task manager using React and Django.
- Developed an API using Django and fetched data from it to display on the website.
- Utilized SQLite as the database management system for the project.

#### Certifications

Python - https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-e617281c-d985-4cea-bfc3-e82e4b4b15ac/

React- https://www.udemv.com/certificate/UC-db57160b-7901-4bd1-8500-40b801f51770/

Find more of my certifications on LinkedIn (https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-mania)

#### **SKILLS**

- Django python framework
- Python
- Javascript(Mongodb, Express, Nodejs), HTML5, CSS3
- SQL(Postgresql, MYSQL, Sqlite, Mongodb)
- Docker(Devops)
- Software Engineering Process
- React

#### REFEREES

Anne Lwenya
President
Deborah Amoi Foundation
dafinternational@gmail.com

+254 798 205 169 +1 (661) 703-2657

# Harun Mbaabu

CEO Lux Tech Academy University of Nairobi mbaabuharun8@gmail.com +254 798 166 628

## Jeremic Arose

Developer Fruitfull Labs arosejeremic5@gmail.com +254 742 518807